There are two sides to every story.
The School for Good and Evil is a fantasy, comedy,
adventure film directed by Paul Feig.
Best friends Sophie and Agatha navigate an enchanted school for young heroes and villains —
and find themselves on opposing sides of the battle between good and evil.
Agatha, played by Sofia Wylie.
Sophie, played by Sophia Anne Caruso.
Professor Dovey, played by Kerry Washington.
Lady Lesso, played by Charlize Theron.
School Master, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Tedros, played by Jamie Flatters.
The School for Good and Evil is a 2022 American fantasy film directed by Paul Feig from a screenplay he
co-wrote with David Magee, based on the 2013 novel of the same name by Soman Chainani.
The film stars an ensemble cast led by Sophia Anne Caruso as Sophie and Sofia Wylie as
Agatha, two best friends who are sent to the Schools for Good and Evil.
After their fortunes are seemingly reversed,
their friendship is put to the test.
The film's development began in 2013, when the rights to the novel were acquired by Roth/Kirschenbaum
Films and Jane Startz Productions, with Universal Pictures initially set to release the film.
After the project languished in development hell, Netflix took over in
2017, and Feig was hired to direct three years later.
Principal photography took place in Northern
Ireland between January and July 2021.
The School for Good and Evil was released on October 19, 2022, by Netflix.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, who criticized the
narrative and storytelling, but praised its cast and visuals.
The film explores themes of school of witchcraft, school, based
on young adult novel, good versus evil, teenager.
The tone is lighthearted.